Stephen Lane-Walsh

System Administrator, Software Engineer, Automation Developer & Curious Hobbiest

Phone: 413 884 5335

Email: sdl.slane@gmail.com **Website:** www.stephenlw.com

GitHub: www.github.com/WhoBrokeTheBuild

Highlights

Linux-focused system administrator with recent experience in Ansible and Docker. Experienced with server and application management across physical and virtualized systems, both in house and cloud based.

Software engineer working with both web and traditional applications such as WordPress websites and C# API development. Interested in a diverse field of technologies including OS/Kernel Development, Electronic Hardware Development, Artificial Intelligence, 3D Graphics Programming, Low-Level Optimization, and Networked Programming.

Work Experience

Aug 2016 - Present

Arduinos, Puzzle Creation, Linux Software Development

Systems Engineer at MyWebGrocer

May 2016 - Present

Linux Administration, Spacewalk, PowerShell Automation Scripting, Docker, Ansible

Software Engineer at MyWebGrocer

2014 - May 2016

WordPress/Tools Development, Server Management, Team Organization/Management

Sr. Web Developer at Berkshire Direct / The White Label Agency

2010 - 2014

Webmaster at Jacques Amand Intl, Ltd / The Tulip Gallery

2009 - 2015

Education

Champlain College, Burlington, VT

2012 - 2016

Bachelors in Computer Science, with a minor in Game/Simulation Programming

Berkshire Community College, Pittsfield, MA

2010

McCann Vocational Technical High School, North Adams, MA

2008 - 2012

System Administration

Highly Experienced: CentOS/RHEL Linux, Windows Server 2008+, Spacewalk, Docker, Ansible, VMWare vSphere, Apache/Nginx, MySQL, Active Directory, DNS, Winbind/Realmd

Proficient: IIS, MSSQL, EMC SAN, Microsoft Exchange, DHCP, Rackspace / Azure Management, Akamai

Programming Languages / Libraries

Highly Experienced: C/C++, PowerShell, C#, Java, Bash, SQL, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, OpenGL/DirectX, OpenAL, Asio, Protobufs, jQuery, WordPress

Proficient: Go, Python, Android, Glib, Arduino, PIC Basic, Assembly, HLSL/GLSL

Development Tools / IDEs

Highly Experienced: Git, SVN, Makefiles/CMake, Atom, Visual Studio, Photoshop/GIMP, Atlassian JIRA/Bitbucket/Crucible

Proficient: Perforce, Mercurial, Flex/Bison, Fossil, IntelliJ, NetBeans, Eclipse

Personal Projects

MMORPG using C++, Asio, and google Flatbuffers.
Suite of web-related servers in C++ (HTTP, FTP, SQL, SMTP, POP)
Multiple iterations of a Game Engine / Library using OpenGL & Lua with a focus on performance.

References

Available Upon Request